<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Camp Sivunniigvik on The Rematriation Project</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/camp-sivunniigvik/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Camp Sivunniigvik on The Rematriation Project</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/camp-sivunniigvik/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Awarded NCSU CHASS Small Seed Grant to Develop Prototype Archiving App</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/2025-05-02-chass-seed-grant/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/2025-05-02-chass-seed-grant/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Great news! NC State University has awarded the team a small seed grant to hire a web developer to create a prototype application that uses mobile texting messaging services as a means for any community members with a mobile phone to submit archival materials directly from their phone via text messages.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We are accepting applications at the moment, and we will be working to create a feasible version of the texting app that can be integrated with this year&amp;rsquo;s Camp Sivunniigvik led by Aqqaluk Trust (AT). AT has devoted significant resources to teaching activities, such as fish netting, berry picking, snare building and other survival skills, to regional youth through programs, such as AT’s Camp Sivunniigvik. The REMA team is currently working with AT’s youth camp, where the texting app prototype would be integrated into their curriculum. AT’s leadership sees this community archiving tool as an exciting new development to connect their digital archiving goals with pre-existing programs in subsistence learning, language revitalization, and transmission of community Elder knowledge and experience to future generations.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
