<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Resources on The Rematriation Project</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/resources/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Resources on The Rematriation Project</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2024 11:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/resources/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>CLIR Postdoc Report</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/2024-08-19-clir-postdoc-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2024 11:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/2024-08-19-clir-postdoc-report/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our now partner, Dr. Erin Yunes, started out as a CLIR (Council on Library and Information Resources) Postdoc Fellow on The Rematriation Project. She wrote a report of her activities, which has been archived by Virginia Tech at &lt;a href=&#34;https://hdl.handle.net/10919/124239&#34;&gt;https://hdl.handle.net/10919/124239&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s the abstract:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The CLIR Postdoctoral Fellowship in Community Data at the Virginia Tech University Libraries (VTUL) was a collaborative initiative designed to help bridge academic resources and community-led projects. The fellowship focused on supporting the Rematriation project through collaboration among scholars and staff from the VT University Libraries and Department of English and community members. A key directive was to work with an Inuit-led interdisciplinary team in creating a digital archive that centers Indigenous knowledges and perspectives. This report provides an overview of the fellowship&amp;rsquo;s objectives, methodologies, key activities, and outcomes, emphasizing the collaborative efforts and innovative approaches that shaped this work.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
