<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>News on The Rematriation Project</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/news/</link>
    <description>Recent content in News on The Rematriation Project</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 11:00:00 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/news/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>New article! &#34;From Notes to Networks: Using Obsidian to Teach Metadata and Linked Data&#34;</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/2025-10-26-from-notes-to-networks-code4lib/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 11:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/2025-10-26-from-notes-to-networks-code4lib/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Great news! Our academic article by Kara Long and Erin Yunes, which was about their collaborative metadata work with Paisaq, was published online today.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;📘 Long, K. &amp;amp; Yunes, E. (2025). From Notes to Networks: Using Obsidian to Teach Metadata and Linked Data. &lt;em&gt;Code4Lib&lt;/em&gt;, 61. &lt;a href=&#34;https://journal.code4lib.org/articles/18535&#34;&gt;https://journal.code4lib.org/articles/18535&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;: In this article, we describe a novel use of the note-taking software Obsidian as a method for users without formal training in metadata creation to develop culturally relevant data literacies across two digital archiving projects. We explain how Obsidian’s built-in use of linked data provides an open-source, flexible, and potentially scalable way for users to creatively interact with digitized materials, navigate and create metadata, and model relationships between digital objects. Furthermore, we demonstrate how Obsidian’s local and offline hosting features can be leveraged to include team members with low or unreliable internet access.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re thankful as well that Mita Williams shared her thoughts about Kara and Erin&amp;rsquo;s work with Paisaq on her blog, &lt;a href=&#34;https://librarian.aedileworks.com/2025/10/22/creating-with-instead-of-creating-for/&#34;&gt;Librarian of Things&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Awarded NCSU CHASS Small Seed Grant to Develop Prototype Archiving App</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/2025-05-02-chass-seed-grant/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/2025-05-02-chass-seed-grant/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Great news! NC State University has awarded the team a small seed grant to hire a web developer to create a prototype application that uses mobile texting messaging services as a means for any community members with a mobile phone to submit archival materials directly from their phone via text messages.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We are accepting applications at the moment, and we will be working to create a feasible version of the texting app that can be integrated with this year&amp;rsquo;s Camp Sivunniigvik led by Aqqaluk Trust (AT). AT has devoted significant resources to teaching activities, such as fish netting, berry picking, snare building and other survival skills, to regional youth through programs, such as AT’s Camp Sivunniigvik. The REMA team is currently working with AT’s youth camp, where the texting app prototype would be integrated into their curriculum. AT’s leadership sees this community archiving tool as an exciting new development to connect their digital archiving goals with pre-existing programs in subsistence learning, language revitalization, and transmission of community Elder knowledge and experience to future generations.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New article! &#34;Reimagining Archives in the Age of Automation&#34;</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/2025-04-17-reimagining-archives/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2025 11:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/2025-04-17-reimagining-archives/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Great news! Another of our co-authored academic articles with Aviññaq and Paisaq was published online today!​&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;📘 Long, K., Itchuaqiyaq, C. U., Lindgren, C. A., Ogier, A., Boyd, L. A., Itchuaqiyaq, D. P., &amp;amp; Yunes, E. (2025). Reimagining Archives in the Age of Automation: A Decolonial and Relational Approach. &lt;em&gt;Technical Communication Quarterly&lt;/em&gt;, 1–17. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1080/10572252.2025.2490506&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1080/10572252.2025.2490506&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;: This article introduces the Relational Approach to Archiving (RAA) as a vital framework to combat the issues posed by data colonialism in traditional archival practices. RAA emphasizes the active involvement of communities in the archival process, ensuring that their cultural knowledge and values guide how materials are preserved and described. The article begins by exploring the challenges of data colonialism and the risks and opportunities of machine-learning technologies in archiving. It then presents RAA as a solution that prioritizes community agency and cultural sensitivity, while also discussing how new technologies can empower community-run archives with careful oversight.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tandfonline.com/eprint/H6ZTMDNNRWYGQCSAGQH4/full?target=10.1080/10572252.2025.2490506&#34;&gt;50 free copies for those with no academic library access&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1080/10572252.2025.2490506&#34;&gt;Link to article for those with academic access&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We hope it moves us all another step in this movement toward rematriation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blanket Toss and Big Wins!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/2025-04-17-blanket-toss-big-wins/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2025 11:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/2025-04-17-blanket-toss-big-wins/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Post originally by Cana Uluak Itchuaqiyaq for &lt;a href=&#34;https://respectfulresearch.com/&#34;&gt;Respectful Research&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Last Friday, something beautiful happened.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Our article, Decolonizing Community-Engaged Research: Designing CER with Cultural Humility as a Foundational Value, received the 2025 CCCC Best Article in the Philosophy or Theory of Technical and Scientific Communication Award.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The article was written by Cana Uluak Itchuaqiyaq (Virginia Tech), Corina Qaaġraq Kramer (&lt;a href=&#34;https://respectfulresearch.com/&#34;&gt;Respectful Research&lt;/a&gt;, Mumik Consulting), and &lt;a href=&#34;https://clndgrn.com&#34;&gt;Chris Lindgren&lt;/a&gt; (North Carolina State University). It’s rooted in our experiences with the Rematriation Project and offers a framework for community-engaged research (CER) based on cultural humility—and on the Inuit practice of nalukataq.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lindgren visits Kotzebue!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/2025-03-04-visit-kotzebue-at/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2025 11:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/2025-03-04-visit-kotzebue-at/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Lindgren visited Kotzebue at the end of February 2025. He and the team wanted to touch base and support Aqqaluk Trust&amp;rsquo;s (AT) work within the community during a very busy and fun time of year in Kotzebue—the regional basketball tournament! The tournament is a great time to visit Kotzebue, since many folks from around the region&amp;rsquo;s 11 other villages travel there to support their teams. While there, Lindgren supported Aqqaluk Trust&amp;rsquo;s work with the community by fielding AT&amp;rsquo;s table at the school&amp;rsquo;s Career &amp;amp; Resource Fair and AT&amp;rsquo;s table on display during the second day of the basketball tournament at the high school.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>REMA Wins National Research Award!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/2025-01-16-cccc-award/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 11:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/2025-01-16-cccc-award/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our team is grateful to hear that one of our articles about our approach to being led by our community partners has been recognized.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Organization&lt;/strong&gt;: NCTE&amp;rsquo;s Conference on College Composition and Communication&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Award&lt;/strong&gt;: 2025 &lt;a href=&#34;https://cccc.ncte.org/cccc/awards/techsci&#34;&gt;CCCC Technical and Scientific Communication Award&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Category&lt;/strong&gt;: Best Article on Philosophy or Theory of Technical or Scientific Communication&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Article&lt;/strong&gt;: Cana Uluak Itchuaqiyaq, Chris A. Lindgren, Corina Qaaġraq Kramer. (2023). Decolonizing Community-Engaged Research: Designing CER with Cultural Humility as a Foundational Value. Communication Design Quarterly, 11(3), 12-20. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1145/3592367.3592369&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1145/3592367.3592369&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Selection Committee comment&lt;/strong&gt;: &amp;ldquo;Arguing that cultural humility &amp;lsquo;is a necessary precondition&amp;rsquo; for effective, respectful community-engaged research (CER), this article extends earlier scholarship by addressing the &amp;lsquo;how&amp;rsquo; of CER. The authors introduce a three-strategy framework for enacting cultural humility in the context of CER, using the ancient Inuit cooperative activity Nalukataq as an extended metaphor. Coupling this metaphor with examples and an applied heuristic, Itchuaqiyaq, Lindgren, and Kramer have gifted the field a practical, actionable theory to improve our work.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Yunes Publishes CLIR Postdoc Report</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/2024-08-19-clir-postdoc-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2024 11:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/2024-08-19-clir-postdoc-report/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our now partner, Dr. Erin Yunes, started out as a CLIR (Council on Library and Information Resources) Postdoc Fellow on The Rematriation Project. She wrote a report of her activities, which has been archived by Virginia Tech at &lt;a href=&#34;https://hdl.handle.net/10919/124239&#34;&gt;https://hdl.handle.net/10919/124239&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s the abstract:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The CLIR Postdoctoral Fellowship in Community Data at the Virginia Tech University Libraries (VTUL) was a collaborative initiative designed to help bridge academic resources and community-led projects. The fellowship focused on supporting the Rematriation project through collaboration among scholars and staff from the VT University Libraries and Department of English and community members. A key directive was to work with an Inuit-led interdisciplinary team in creating a digital archive that centers Indigenous knowledges and perspectives. This report provides an overview of the fellowship&amp;rsquo;s objectives, methodologies, key activities, and outcomes, emphasizing the collaborative efforts and innovative approaches that shaped this work.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US Indigenous Data Sovereignty Network Summit</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/2024-04-15-ids-summit/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2024 11:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/2024-04-15-ids-summit/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Part of the team was able to present and network at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://usindigenousdatanetwork.org/us-indigenous-data-sovereignty-governance-summit/&#34;&gt;2024 US Indigenous Data Sovereignty Network Summit&lt;/a&gt; in Tucson, AZ. We all were able to meet other folks doing amazing IDSov and IDGov work from across the US and beyond.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;team.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;2.webp&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;2.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;3.webp&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;4.webp&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;4.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;6.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Team visits Kotzebue, Alaska!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/2023-04-15-visit-kotz/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2023 11:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/2023-04-15-visit-kotz/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Part of the team was hosted by our community partner, Corina, in Kotzebue in April 2023.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We were able to visit our partners at Aqqaluk Trust, meet face-to-face for the first time altogether, and discuss AT&amp;rsquo;s vision for the NANA region. Lance Kramer (in the second picture below) also explained some of his ideas about curriculum that centers cultural and historical subsistence practices.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;at_1.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;at_2.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Cana also brought us around Kotzebue to gather a better sense of the everyday life and context. For instance, we actually saw the inflated prices of groceries in the store, due to distribution costs.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
