<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>News on The Rematriation Project</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/news/</link>
    <description>Recent content in News on The Rematriation Project</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 11:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/news/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>REMA Wins National Research Award!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/2025-01-16-cccc-award/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 11:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/2025-01-16-cccc-award/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our team is grateful to hear that one of our articles about our approach to being led by our community partners has been recognized.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Organization&lt;/strong&gt;: NCTE&amp;rsquo;s Conference on College Composition and Communication&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Award&lt;/strong&gt;: 2025 &lt;a href=&#34;https://cccc.ncte.org/cccc/awards/techsci&#34;&gt;CCCC Technical and Scientific Communication Award&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Category&lt;/strong&gt;: Best Article on Philosophy or Theory of Technical or Scientific Communication&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Article&lt;/strong&gt;: Cana Uluak Itchuaqiyaq, Chris A. Lindgren, Corina Qaaġraq Kramer. (2023). Decolonizing Community-Engaged Research: Designing CER with Cultural Humility as a Foundational Value. Communication Design Quarterly, 11(3), 12-20. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1145/3592367.3592369&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1145/3592367.3592369&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Selection Committee comment&lt;/strong&gt;: &amp;ldquo;Arguing that cultural humility &amp;lsquo;is a necessary precondition&amp;rsquo; for effective, respectful community-engaged research (CER), this article extends earlier scholarship by addressing the &amp;lsquo;how&amp;rsquo; of CER. The authors introduce a three-strategy framework for enacting cultural humility in the context of CER, using the ancient Inuit cooperative activity Nalukataq as an extended metaphor. Coupling this metaphor with examples and an applied heuristic, Itchuaqiyaq, Lindgren, and Kramer have gifted the field a practical, actionable theory to improve our work.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
