<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>News on The Rematriation Project</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/news/</link>
    <description>Recent content in News on The Rematriation Project</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 11:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/news/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>REMA Wins National Research Award!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/2025-01-16-cccc-award/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 11:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/2025-01-16-cccc-award/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our team is grateful to hear that one of our articles about our approach to being led by our community partners has been recognized.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Organization&lt;/strong&gt;: NCTE&amp;rsquo;s Conference on College Composition and Communication&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Award&lt;/strong&gt;: 2025 &lt;a href=&#34;https://cccc.ncte.org/cccc/awards/techsci&#34;&gt;CCCC Technical and Scientific Communication Award&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Category&lt;/strong&gt;: Best Article on Philosophy or Theory of Technical or Scientific Communication&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Article&lt;/strong&gt;: Cana Uluak Itchuaqiyaq, Chris A. Lindgren, Corina Qaaġraq Kramer. (2023). Decolonizing Community-Engaged Research: Designing CER with Cultural Humility as a Foundational Value. Communication Design Quarterly, 11(3), 12-20. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1145/3592367.3592369&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1145/3592367.3592369&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Selection Committee comment&lt;/strong&gt;: &amp;ldquo;Arguing that cultural humility &amp;lsquo;is a necessary precondition&amp;rsquo; for effective, respectful community-engaged research (CER), this article extends earlier scholarship by addressing the &amp;lsquo;how&amp;rsquo; of CER. The authors introduce a three-strategy framework for enacting cultural humility in the context of CER, using the ancient Inuit cooperative activity Nalukataq as an extended metaphor. Coupling this metaphor with examples and an applied heuristic, Itchuaqiyaq, Lindgren, and Kramer have gifted the field a practical, actionable theory to improve our work.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CLIR Postdoc Report</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/2024-08-19-clir-postdoc-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2024 11:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/2024-08-19-clir-postdoc-report/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our now partner, Dr. Erin Yunes, started out as a CLIR (Council on Library and Information Resources) Postdoc Fellow on The Rematriation Project. She wrote a report of her activities, which has been archived by Virginia Tech at &lt;a href=&#34;https://hdl.handle.net/10919/124239&#34;&gt;https://hdl.handle.net/10919/124239&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s the abstract:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The CLIR Postdoctoral Fellowship in Community Data at the Virginia Tech University Libraries (VTUL) was a collaborative initiative designed to help bridge academic resources and community-led projects. The fellowship focused on supporting the Rematriation project through collaboration among scholars and staff from the VT University Libraries and Department of English and community members. A key directive was to work with an Inuit-led interdisciplinary team in creating a digital archive that centers Indigenous knowledges and perspectives. This report provides an overview of the fellowship&amp;rsquo;s objectives, methodologies, key activities, and outcomes, emphasizing the collaborative efforts and innovative approaches that shaped this work.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
